<resources>
    <string name="app_name">San Francisco Visitors Guide</string>
    <!-- TabLayout titles -->
    <string name="tab1HistoricalSites">Historical Sites</string>
    <string name="tab2Restaurants">Restaurants</string>
    <string name="tab3LocalEvents">Local Events</string>
    <string name="tab4FamilyEvents">Family Events</string>

    <!-- names and descriptions of Historical Sites  -->
    <string name="goldenGateBridgeName">Golden Gate Bridge</string>
    <string name="goldenGateBridgeDescription">The Golden Gate Bridge is a suspension bridge spanning the Golden Gate, the one-mile-wide (1.6 km) strait connecting San Francisco Bay and the Pacific Ocean. The structure links the American city of San Francisco, California – the northern tip of the San Francisco Peninsula – to Marin County, carrying both U.S. Route 101 and California State Route 1 across the strait. The bridge is one of the most internationally recognized symbols of San Francisco, California, and the United States. It has been declared one of the Wonders of the Modern World by the American Society of Civil Engineers.\n\nThe Frommer\'s travel guide describes the Golden Gate Bridge as \"possibly the most beautiful, certainly the most photographed, bridge in the world.\" At the time of its opening in 1937, it was both the longest and the tallest suspension bridge in the world, with a main span of 4,200 feet (1,280 m) and a total height of 746 feet (227 m).</string>
    <string name="alcatrazName">Alcatraz</string>
    <string name="alcatrazDescription">The Alcatraz Federal Penitentiary or United States Penitentiary, Alcatraz Island (often just referred to as Alcatraz or The Rock) was a maximum high-security federal prison on Alcatraz Island, 1.25 miles (2.01 km) off the coast of San Francisco, California, which operated from August 11, 1934, until March 21, 1963.\n\nThe main prison building was built in 1910–1912 during its time as a United States Army military prison; Alcatraz had been the site of a citadel since the 1860s. The United States Disciplinary Barracks, Pacific Branch on Alcatraz was acquired by the United States Department of Justice on October 12, 1933, and the island became a prison of the Federal Bureau of Prisons in August 1934 after the buildings were modernized to meet the requirements of a top-notch security prison. Given this high security and the location of Alcatraz in the cold waters and strong currents of San Francisco Bay, the prison operators believed Alcatraz to be escape-proof and America's strongest prison.</string>
    <string name="fortMasonName">Fort Mason</string>
    <string name="fortMasonDescription">Fort Mason, once known as San Francisco Port of Embarkation, US Army, in San Francisco, California, is a former United States Army post located in the northern Marina District, alongside San Francisco Bay. Fort Mason served as an Army post for more than 100 years, initially as a coastal defense site[3] and subsequently as a military port facility. During World War II, it was the principal port for the Pacific campaign.\n\nToday it is part of the Golden Gate National Recreation Area and the site of several cultural facilities. The entire fort area is listed as a historic district on the National Register of Historic Places,[2] with over 49 buildings of historic significance, spread over 1,200 acres (490 ha). while the lower port area is a National Historic Landmark District, designated for its role in World War II.</string>
    <string name="coitTowerName">Coit Tower</string>
    <string name="coitTowerDescription">Coit Tower is a 210-foot (64 m) tower in the Telegraph Hill neighborhood of San Francisco, California. The tower, in the city\'s Pioneer Park, was built between 1932 and 1933 using Lillie Hitchcock Coit\'s bequest to beautify the city of San Francisco. It was added to the National Register of Historic Places on January 29, 2008.\n\nThe art deco tower, built of unpainted reinforced concrete, was designed by architects Arthur Brown, Jr. and Henry Howard. The interior features fresco murals in the American Social Realism style, painted by 27 different on-site artists and their numerous assistants, plus two additional paintings installed after creation off-site.\n\nAlso known as the Coit Memorial Tower, it was dedicated to the volunteer firemen who had died in San Francisco's five major fires. Although an apocryphal story claims that the tower was designed to resemble a fire hose nozzle[4] due to Coit\'s affinity with the San Francisco firefighters of the day, the resemblance is coincidental</string>
    <string name="ferryBuildingName">Ferry Building</string>
    <string name="ferryBuildingDescription">The San Francisco Ferry Building is a terminal for ferries that travel across the San Francisco Bay, a food hall and an office building. It is located on The Embarcadero in San Francisco, California.\n\nOn top of the building is a 245-foot-tall (75 m) clock tower with four clock dials, each 22 feet (6.7 m) in diameter, which can be seen from Market Street, a main thoroughfare of the city.\n\nDesigned in 1892 by American architect A. Page Brown in the Beaux Arts style, the ferry building was completed in 1898. At its opening, it was the largest project undertaken in the city up to that time. Brown designed the clock tower after the 12th-century Giralda bell tower in Seville, Spain, and the entire length of the building on both frontages is based on an arched arcade.\n\nWith decreased use since the 1950s, after bridges were constructed carry transbay traffic and most streetcar routes were converted to busses, the building was adapted to office use and its public spaces broken up. In 2002, a restoration and renovation were undertaken to redevelop the entire complex. The 660-foot-long (200 m) Great Nave was restored, together with its height and materials. A marketplace was created on the ground floor, the former baggage handling area. The second and third floors were adapted for office and Port Commission use. During daylight, on every full and half-hour, the clock bell chimes portions of the Westminster Quarters. The ferry terminal is a designated San Francisco landmark and is listed on the National Register of Historic Places.</string>

    <!-- names and descriptions of Restaurants -->
    <string name="cliffHouseName">Cliff House</string>
    <string name="cliffHouseDescription">With its staggering views of the coastline and the ruins of the Sutro Baths, this SF icon has undergone a long series of fires, rebuildings, shutters, and reopenings to achieve its current crown-jewel status. It\'s a little oasis at the end of the world.</string>
    <string name="houseOfPrimeRibName">House of Prime Rib</string>
    <string name="houseOfPrimeRibDescription">No San Francisco carnivore has truly lived before eating a juicy slice of prime rib off the cart in this \'50s throwback, where the cocktails come with their own shakers, the salad is spun tableside, and the baked potatoes are always at least 50% sour cream.</string>
    <string name="tommysJoyntName">Tommy\'s Joynt</string>
    <string name="tommysJoyntDescription">One of the Bay Area\'s last remaining old-school hofbraus, Tommy\'s is known for low prices, free-flowing beer, and meat aplenty. Local and organic it is not, but for rib-sticking basics, it\'s hard to beat, especially late-night when regulars flow in for carved roast beef and other delights.</string>
    <string name="zuniCafeName">Zuni Cafe</string>
    <string name="zuniCafeDescription">One of the Bay Area\'s last remaining old-school hofbraus, Tommy\'s is known for low prices, free-flowing beer, and meat aplenty. Local and organic it is not, but for rib-sticking basics, it\'s hard to beat, especially late-night when regulars flow in for carved roast beef and other delights.</string>
    <string name="tadichGrillName">Tadich Grill</string>
    <string name="tadichGrillDescription">Founded in 1849, this isn\'t just San Francisco\'s oldest restaurant, but California\'s as well, and it has the old-school atmosphere to go with that laurel. White-coated waiters, a menu boasting local classics from hangtown fry to cioppino to sand dabs, and a bumping central bar all add to the pleasure.</string>

    <!-- names and descriptions of Annual Events -->
    <string name="howWeirdStreeFaireName">How Weird Street Faire</string>
    <string name="howWeirdStreeFaireDescription">The How Weird Street Faire is a menagerie of attractions, including a world renowned music festival featuring 10 stages of different styles of dance music, an open air art festival filling an expanded Art Alley, a unique market of interesting vendors and delicious food, and a platform for performers of every type. The faire is from Noon to 8pm. Get there early to enjoy all of the fun.</string>
    <string name="bayToBreakersName">Bay to Breakers</string>
    <string name="bayToBreakersDescription">Each year the race is a glorious celebration of the human spirit – a giant wave of athleticism, fun, frivolity, and determination flowing across the City from the Bay to the Pacific Ocean. Bay to Breakers is one of the largest footraces in the world with 40,000 + participants and 100,000 + spectators annually. As the race grew in size it even set a Guinness Book world-record, with 110,000 participants in 1986. The course is challenging and beautiful, and consistently attracts world-class competitors. But, it isn’t just a race for the serious runner.</string>
    <string name="outsideLandsName">Outside Lands</string>
    <string name="outsideLandsDescription">Outside Lands Works is a charitable fund that invests in the cultural vitality of the Bay Area through grants to regional music and arts education programs. \n\nOutside Lands Works giving program was launched to fund nonprofit music and arts education programs and raise the profile of these pioneering organizations among festival fans and audiences. Your financial support of Outside Lands Works helps us carry out our mission to invest in Bay Area music and arts education programs</string>
    <string name="sanFranciscoPrideName">San Francisco Pride</string>
    <string name="sanFranciscoPrideDescription">The Mission of the San Francisco Lesbian Gay Bisexual Transgender Pride Celebration Committee is to educate the world, commemorate our heritage, celebrate our culture, and liberate our people.\n\nWith over 200 parade contingents and exhibitors, and more than twenty community-run stages and venues, the San Francisco Pride Celebration and Parade is the largest gathering of the LGBT community and allies in the nation.</string>
    <string name="chineseNewYearName">Chinese New Year</string>
    <string name="chineseNewYearDescription">Recognized as one of the top ten parades in the world by IFEA, the International Festivals and Events Association, the Chinese New Year Parade and Festival in Shaky Town is the largest celebration of Asian culture outside Asia, and offers one of the last remaining night time, illuminated parades in the USA. Attracting thousands of fans each year, the parade features a wealth of elaborate floats and costumes, traditional “lions”, the ever popular 270-foot Golden Dragon operated by over 100 mean and women, fireworks and the presentation of the new Miss Chinatown USA and her court.</string>

    <!-- names and descriptions of Family Events -->
    <string name="pier39Name">Pier 39</string>
    <string name="pier39Description">PIER 39 is the premiere entertainment destination in the heart of the San Francisco waterfront.  Along with two levels of dining, entertainment, shopping and attractions both on The PIER and in San Francisco Bay, PIER 39 is home to the world-famous sea lions, who have been delighting guests daily at K-Dock since 1990.\n\nThe PIER is a gathering place for millions of guests annually.  With picture perfect views of the Golden Gate and Bay Bridges, Alcatraz and the city skyline at almost every turn, it is easy to see why PIER 39 has recently been named the most visited attraction in San Francisco for the ninth consecutive year.  A visit to San Francisco starts at The PIER!</string>
    <string name="metreonName">Metreon</string>
    <string name="metreonDescription">The Metreon is a shopping center located in downtown San Francisco at the corner of 4th Street and Mission Street. It is a four-story 350,000 square foot (33,000 m²) building built over the corner of the underground Moscone Center convention center. Metreon opened on June 16, 1999, as the first of a proposed chain of Sony "urban entertainment centers", aggregating dining, gaming, music, exhibitions, shopping, and movies. Sony intended the ambitious 85 million dollar project to be not only a theme park and gallery for Sony products but also a way to reinforce a sophisticated image for the Sony brand.\n\nIn 2006 Metreon was sold to Westfield, a mall developer, and it was refashioned as a food-oriented mall. In 2011, with few exceptions, remaining businesses in the mall were closed. Westfield began a major renovation with an emphasis on dining, including Target creating a large downtown department store that now takes up the second floor. In April, 2012, the Westfield sold the Metreon to Starwood Capital Group.[1] Westfield currently continues to be responsible for management.</string>
    <string name="sanFranciscoZooName">San Francisco Zoo</string>
    <string name="sanFranciscoZooDescription">The San Francisco Zoo is a 100-acre (40 ha) zoo located in the southwestern corner of San Francisco, California, between Lake Merced and the Pacific Ocean along the Great Highway. The zoo\'s main entrance, once located on the north side across Sloat Boulevard and one block south of the Muni Metro L Taraval line, is now to the west on the ocean side of the zoo off of the Great Highway.\n\nThis zoo is the birthplace of Koko the gorilla, and, since 1974, the home of Elly, the oldest black rhinoceros in North America.[3] It houses more than 1000 individual animals representing over 250 species, as of 2016</string>
    <string name="exploratoriumName">Exploratorium</string>
    <string name="exploratoriumDescription">The totally reimagined Exploratorium in its new waterfront home at Pier 15 is nothing short of spectacular. Named by CNN as the #1 Spot for Kids in the country, the museum encourages guests of all ages to touch, explore and play with 600 exhibits. Investigate the living world, experiment with thoughts, feelings and behavior, explore the local environment, think with your hands and much more. All this science making you hungry? The Exploratorium houses a cafe and a waterfront restaurant, both serving seasonal and sustainable cuisine prepared by local chefs.</string>
    <string name="californiaAcademyOfSciencesName">California Academy of Sciences</string>
    <string name="californiaAcademyOfSciencesDescription">The California Academy of Sciences is a research institute and natural history museum in San Francisco, California, that is among the largest museums of natural history in the world, housing over 26 million specimens.[2] The Academy began in 1853 as a learned society and still carries out a large amount of original research.[3] It is California\'s oldest museum.\n\nCompletely rebuilt in 2008, the building covers 400,000 square feet (37,000 square metres).[2] The primary building in Golden Gate Park reopened on September 27, 2008</string>
</resources>
